copyright.com 2019-09-26

# Privacy Policy - Copyright Clearance Center

**Effective: 16 April 2019**

This Privacy Policy applies to www.copyright.com, owned and operated by Copyright Clearance Center (“CCC”). This Privacy Policy describes how Copyright Clearance Center collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web site: www.copyright.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

**COLLECTION OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**

You may access and read most material on CCC’s Web sites without giving us any information that identifies you. However, when you engage in certain activities on these Web sites, we may ask you to provide certain information about yourself and/or your organization by filling out and submitting an online form. These activities include accessing educational sessions, whitepapers and other high-value content or seeking and receiving permissions, authorizations or licenses to use the copyrighted works of the copyright rightsholders we represent. It is completely optional for you to fill out the form and/or engage in these activities.

This information enables CCC to provide you with the permission, authorization or license you are seeking. Should you choose not to do so, however, it may not be possible for CCC to provide those services to you.

Should you choose to take advantage of our services, we may require that you provide us with personally identifiable information, such as your name, organization name, mailing address, e-mail address and phone number. Should you choose to pay with a credit card, you may be asked to provide a card number, expiration date and the name and address of the cardholder. If you add an additional user to your account, we will ask for the additional user’s name, phone number, fax, and e-mail address. For more information about data security, please see the Security section of this Privacy Policy.

CCC collects all of this information in order to record and support your licensing and other activities. For example, we may use the information you provide to verify the details of a license issued to you or to keep you informed about our products and services. We may supplement the information you provide with commercially available demographic and address information in order to enhance our ability to serve you.

Please note that in some cases you may access CCC’s services through the site of a participating copyright rightsholder, such as a publisher, or one of our integration partners, such as a course management system provider. In those cases, you will be directed to a Web page within a CCC Web site, and it is CCC that will be collecting your information, even though you may continue to see the copyright rightsholder’s branding or logo. CCC will share information with the copyright rightsholder as described in the Use of Personally Identifiable Information section of this Privacy Policy.

**USE OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**

Information We May Share:  
CCC shares the information that you provide to us in accordance with our obligations to copyright rightsholders to identify uses of their copyrighted materials. These obligations vary from CCC program to program. Details about such obligations under any particular CCC program are available upon request. CCC does NOT, however, share information with copyright rightsholders (i) about credit card details, or (ii) about the use of OTHER copyright rightsholders’ copyrighted materials.

If you have identified yourself or are identified by your employer to CCC as being associated with a CCC-participating organization, you may receive promotional communications from CCC either directly from us or through your participating organization. Further, when you use your organization’s credit card or CCC billing account to transact business with us, the organization will receive information about the materials you have used and reported to CCC. Similarly, in circumstances where multiple individuals associated with the same organization share a single CCC account or a single user name and password, each individual may have access to information provided by the other individuals on the same account.

Please note that we may use outside shipping and printing companies to fulfill orders, and a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services. These companies are not authorized by CCC to retain, share, store or use the personally identifiable information that they receive from CCC for any other purposes. These companies are authorized to use your personally identifiable information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content to/from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to CCC.

If CCC is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information.

CCC recognizes and appreciates the importance of the responsible use of your personally identifiable information. Except as disclosed above or in published lists of consenting customers, we do not release or sell lists of our customer names to outside organizations. Further, your personally identifiable information is password-protected to prevent unauthorized access to it. Finally, when you submit personally identifiable information to CCC, you understand and agree that CCC and its subsidiaries, affiliates and trusted vendors may transfer, store and process your customer profile in any country in which we do business, including but not limited to the United States. In the event that we transfer your information in such circumstances, we remain responsible for taking steps intended to ensure that the information continues to receive appropriate protections.

Disclosure in Response to Lawful Requests: In certain situations, CCC may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or legal process.

Please be advised that CCC is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of any other Web sites to which copyright.com or any other CCC Web site may link.

**USE OF COOKIES AND OTHER TECHNOLOGIES**

We and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers use cookies and similar technologies in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference) and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

As with most Web sites, CCC also gathers certain information automatically and stores it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, and a date/time stamp and clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.  We do not honor Do Not Track requests at this time, due to the lack of a clear industry standard. This privacy policy may be revised when a common definition and standard is adopted.

When you accept our cookies, we use them to track your visit to any CCC Web offering. In addition, we use log files and clear gifs to help manage our Web site and other electronic communications. However, none of this information, other than the automated log-in feature, identifies you personally or is tied to any of your personally identifiable information. You remain anonymous unless you have otherwise provided CCC with personally identifiable information.

We partner with a third-party ad network to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt out by clicking here: <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/>. Please note this does not opt you out of general advertising being served to you and you will continue to receive generic ads.

**TESTIMONIALS**  
We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. You can contact us at [info@copyright.com](mailto:info@copyright.com).

**SOCIAL MEDIA  
**Our Web site includes Social Media, such as the Facebook and Twitter buttons or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Social Media features may collect your IP address, locate the page you are visiting on our site, and set a cookie to enable the Social Media to function properly. Social Media are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Social Media are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**CHANGING OUR RECORDS OF YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**  
Upon request CCC will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. To request this information please contact us at [privacy@copyright.com](mailto:privacy@copyright.com).

You have the right to request that we correct or delete your personally identifiable information. This may be accomplished either directly on our Web site on those screens that allow you to edit your personally identifiable information; by writing to CCC at: Copyright Clearance Center, Inc., Customer Relations Department, 222 Rosewood Drive, Danvers, Massachusetts 01923, USA; or by e-mailing us at [info@copyright.com](mailto:info@copyright.com). We will respond to your request promptly.

When you contact us, please include your name, address and/or e-mail address, account number (if known) and a detailed explanation of your request.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with services. If you request to deactivate your account or delete personal information, we will endeavor to fulfill your request, but some personal information may persist in backup copies for a certain period of time and may be retained as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**OPTING IN TO RECEIVE INFORMATION FROM CCC**  
CCC regularly distributes communications via email and direct mail regarding upcoming webinars and other events, news about our products and services and informative content on related topics. If you wish to receive this type of information in the future, please complete the form [found here](https://www.rightsdirect.com/pardot-landing-page/opt-in-page/).

**OPTING OUT OF RECEIVING INFORMATION FROM CCC**  
CCC follows industry standard safe unsubscribe practices. You have the right to opt out of receiving marketing communications and newsletters from CCC by following the “unsubscribe” instructions that come with each message from us. In addition, you may opt out of receiving such communications by writing to us at: Copyright Clearance Center, Inc., Marketing Department, 222 Rosewood Drive, Danvers, Massachusetts 01923, USA; by e-mailing us at [marketing@copyright.com](mailto:marketing@copyright.com); or by telephoning us at 978-750-8400 and asking to speak with the Marketing Department .

**REFERRALS  
**If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. CCC stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.

Your friend may contact us at [info@copyright.com](mailto:info@copyright.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

**SINGLE SIGN-ON**  
You can log in to our website using sign-in services using your corporate username. These services will authenticate your identity, provide you the option to share certain personal information (such as your name and e-mail address) with us, and to pre-populate our sign-up form.

**SECURITY**  
The security of your personally identifiable information is important to us. The password that protects your personally identifiable information, as well as your credit card information, is encrypted during transmission using secure socket layer (SSL) technology, which is widely used on the Internet for this purpose. These data are also stored in encrypted form.

CCC adheres to generally accepted industry standards to protect this information, both during transmission and once we receive it. These standards include the use of leading hardware and software applications. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your applicable information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can e-mail us at [info@copyright.com](mailto:info@copyright.com), or contact our Privacy Officer at [privacy@copyright.com](mailto:privacy@copyright.com) _._ You may also contact our Privacy Officer with any questions or comments about this privacy policy. If at any time you believe that we have not adhered to this privacy policy or you have a complaint regarding the way your personally identifiable information is being handled, please contact the Privacy Officer. Disputes under this privacy policy will be resolved by the Privacy Officer, who will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly investigate and, if necessary, correct any problem.

**Privacy Officer  
Copyright Clearance Center  
222 Rosewood Drive  
Danvers, MA 01923 USA  
Email: **[ **privacy@copyright.com**](mailto:privacy@copyright.com)

**OUR COMMITMENT TO YOUR PRIVACY**

CCC  and  Ixxus North America, Inc, its wholly owned subsidiary, comply with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. CCC has certified to the Department of Commerce that it and Ixxus North America, Inc. adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles and is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, CCC  and Ixxus North America, Inc. commit to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information, to providing you with information about how you can limit the use or disclosure of your personal data. and may be liable for onward transfers of your data made without your consent.

EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Private Shield policy should first contact CCC at: [privacyofficer@copyright.com](mailto:privacyofficer@copyright.com). CCC  and Ixxus North America, Inc. have further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to our alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request> for more information or to file a complaint. The third party dispute resolution services are provided at no cost to you. Should the third party dispute resolution be unable to resolve any issues or disputes, you may invoke the option under the Privacy Shield of binding arbitration. For more information, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=G-Arbitration-Procedures>

**GDPR**  
CCC policies and practices are consistent with those required under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR, 2016/679) for companies doing business in the European Union.  To learn more about the GDPR, please visit our [FAQs on the topic](http://www.copyright.com/pardot-landing-page/data-collection-practices-faqs/) or our [Data Collection Practices Page](http://www.copyright.com/pardot-landing-page/data-collection-practices/). To learn more about the GDPR you can access the official document [here](https://gdpr-info.eu/).

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**  
When we make any material change to this Privacy Policy, we will inform you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by posting a notice on the homepage of [www.copyright.com](http://www.copyright.com/) prior to the change becoming effective. We will on our homepage for 30 days, thereafter, stating that the policy has been updated and we will change the date on this page, noting when the policy was last updated.
